I think the hardest thing of all
is not being angry.
Throughout time,
we've been lied to,
we've been told half truths
and information has been hidden from us.
They've made us feel furious, and they've made us feel ashamed.
Despite everything,
we are here,
and we've put ourselves together as best we could.
I believe we've built our identity and our history
through our every day actions.
Generally speaking, we are alone.
I mean,
it's only us.
We don't know much about those that came before us,
that history is made of scraps that at this point have become shreds.
More than once, we picked up the pieces and tried to make them fit,
but it turns out we are alone.
It's difficult for me,
to look away from the systemic violence and the dehumanization.
I also can't overlook the fact
that our country's history, with it's coups
and the tireless fucking right,
laid down the framework of our history as a family.
I believe that what's important is that despite all the pain,
our bond is one of love.
I also believe that having such a peronist mother
it's impossible to foster a bond of anything but love.
I suspect that my mom looked for her family where she could:
in her neighborhood,
in the union,
and in our compañerxs.
We have fought together against oblivion and time.
We have also fought together against whoever we had to.
We have screamed and we've thrown stones against some piece of shit's windows.
We have marched under the rain and under the sun,
sometimes alone,
sometimes in a sea of compañerxs.
We've spent our lives cursing, kicking and being mad,
but together.
Overall, I think
that we're left with what we've done, and not with what's been told to us.
I think about the fact that despite everything,
we are here.